# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello everyone, this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我和大家分享
In this video, I'll share the recipe of
# 水煮鸡片
Sichuan Boiled Chicken
# 首先我们准备新鲜的鸡胸肉二两（100克）
First, we prepare fresh chicken breast (100g)
# 将鸡胸肉的筋膜去除干净备用
Remove the fibrous tissue and set it aside
# 这一步的目的是提升菜品的口感
This is to enhance the texture of the dish
# 然后切碎备用
Then mince and prepare
# 下一步开始处理
Next, we continue to cook
# 首先将鸡胸肉放入料理机
First, put chicken breast in the blender
# 然后加入冰水100克
Then add 100g of iced water
# 清水的量和鸡胸肉为1:1
Roughly as much water as the chicken breast
# 加入食用盐3克
Add 3g of salt
# 然后将鸡胸肉搅成肉泥
Then start the blender until the chicken breast is blended evenly
# 这一步必须加冰水降温否则肌纤维容易失去弹性
At this step, we must add iced water to cool down; otherwise, muscle fibers easily lose its elasticity
# 搅成肉泥之后下一步开始调制
After it becomes paste-like, we prepare the ingredients according to proportion.
# 盆中加入蛋清240克
Add 240g of egg white to a bowl
# 拌匀之后顺着一个方向搅拌5分钟
Mix and stir in the same direction for 5 minutes
# 同学们蛋清的量不能太多也不能太少
We need just the right amount of egg white
# 蛋清和鸡肉蓉拌均之后下一步开始调淀粉糊
After mixing the egg white with chicken, we start to prepare diluted starch
# 盆中加入土豆淀粉240克
Add 240g of potato starch to the bowl
# 加入清水200克之后将淀粉拌匀备用
Add 200g of water and mix it with the starch
# 淀粉拌匀之后倒入鸡肉泥种拌匀备用
After mixing, add the minced chicken, mix again and set aside
# 同学们配料的详细比列会在视频尾部
The detailed ratios of ingredients are displayed at the end of this video
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next, start preparing the minor ingredients.
# 准备绿豆芽150克
Prepare 150g of green bean sprouts
# 准备青蒜2根斜刀切成小段备用
Prepare two garlic sprouts and slant-cut it to small slices
# 准备适量的鲜菇撕开备用
Prepare some fresh mushrooms and shred them
# 准备适量的干辣椒剪成小节备用
Prepare some dried chili pepper and cut them into small pieces
# 碗中加入几颗青花椒备用
Add a few Sichuan green peppercorn to the bowl
# 最后拍几颗大蒜剁成蒜末备用
Finally, crush a few garlic gloves and mince them
# 下一步开始制作
Next, start to prepare the dish
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, we heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入小宽油
After the wok is heated, add a small amount of Kuan You (literally "broad oil")
# 油温烧至大约70度之后即可（2成油温）
Until the oil reaches around 70 degrees
# 然后用炒勺少量多次的将鸡肉泥从锅边淋入
Then add the chicken mix from the side of the wok with the frying spoon, limiting to a small amount each time
# 转小火将鸡片炸至飘起来之后捞出备用
Switch to low heat, fry the chicken until it floats, and take it out
# 同学们这一步必须保持低油温
Make sure the oil stays at a low temperature
# 否则容易将鸡片炸老
Otherwise it's easy to over-fry
# 再加入清水烧开之后将鸡片下锅焯水几秒钟
Then add water to boil and parboil the chicken for several seconds
# 这一步的目的是减少鸡片中的油脂
This is to reduce the chicken fat
# 焯好水之后倒出备用
After parboiling, pour it out and set aside
# 锅中加入少许的底油烧热
Add a little base oil and heat up the wok
# 油温烧热之后加入花椒辣椒和蒜末爆香
After the oil heats up, add Sichuan peppercorn, dried chili pepper, and minced garlic until the smell comes out
# 料头爆香之后加入豆芽等辅料炒至断生
After that, add bean sprouts and other minor ingredients then stir-fry them until softened
# 中途加入食用盐和鸡精调味
Add salt and chicken broth powder midway
# 调好味之后倒入碗中垫底备用
After seasoning, pour to a bowl and spread it over the bottom
# 然后锅中再次加入适量的底油烧热
Then add some base oil to the wok again and heat it up
# 油温5成热之后加入料头爆香（干辣椒，花椒，蒜末）
After the oil reaches 160 degrees, add minor ingredients until the smell comes out (dried chili pepper, Sichuan peppercorn, and minced garlic)
料头爆香之后加入红油豆瓣酱15克炒香炒出红油
# Then add 15g of chili oil doubanjiang until the oil turns red
# 豆瓣酱炒香之后加入适量的清水开大火烧开、
Next, add some water and turn to high heat until it boils
# 大火烧开之后开始调味
After it boils, start seasoning
# 锅中加入食用盐4克
Add 4g of salt to the wok
# 加入鸡精2克
Add 2g of chicken broth powder
# 加入少许白糖和胡椒粉调味
Add a little sugar and ground pepper to season
# 最后将鸡片下锅小火煮1分钟煮至入味
Finally, add the chicken to the wok and boil with low heat for 1 minute until it's fully seasoned
# 1分钟之后将鸡片捞出放入盆中
After 1 minute, take the chicken out to the bowl
# 下一步开始准备泼油
Next, start to prepare to apply oil
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的植物油烧至7成热
Heat up the wok and add some vegetable oil until it reaches 200 degrees
# 油温7成热之后盛出半勺
After the oil heats up, fill half a frying spoon
# 炒勺中加入剩余的花椒辣椒和蒜末炸香
Add extra Sichuan peppercorn, dried chili pepper, and minced garlic until the aroma comes out
# 料头炸香之后再泼在鸡片上面即可
Then pour the fried minor ingredients onto the chicken
# 一道口感爽嫩的水煮鸡片就制作完成
We've completed preparing a tender and refreshing dish, Sichuan Boiled Chicken.
# 下面开始技术总结
Now, we summarize the key techniques
# 第一，鸡胸肉中的筋膜必须去除干净，这样才能有效提升口感
Firstly, we must remove the fibrous tissue to have the ideal texture
# 第二，此菜最好用料理机搅拌这样更加细腻
Secondly, the blender mixes the chicken more smoothly
# 第三，详细比列为：鸡肉100克加水100克加盐3克搅拌成肉泥，然后加蛋清240克和肉泥搅拌均匀，另外土豆淀粉240克加清水200克拌匀，最后用鸡肉泥和湿淀粉搅拌均匀即可
Thirdly, the detailed proportion for the mixture is the following: Add 100g of water and 3g of salt to 100g of chicken and mix it, then add 240g of egg yolk and mix again, then mix 240g of potato starch with 200g of water, and finally mix the diluted starch and the minced chicken.
# 水煮鸡片的技术总结完毕
Above is all techniques for Sichuan Boiled Chicken.